Naveed Gujral Designer/Developer

www.linkedin.com/in/naveed-gujral naveedgujral93@gmail.com github.com/NaveedGujral naveedgujral.co.uk Nottingham, UK 07954 048 430

in

 \bowtie

About

I'm a digital designer and developer with a background in product design that enjoys client-facing roles with an emphasis on user centred design. I have a variety of experience designing and developing physical and digital products for a number of clients. As a confident self-starter I keep abreast of current design trends and get excited by learning new technologies. I thrive in collaborative environments, especially on projects that intersect technology and design.

Experience

Designer/Developer | Visual

Mar 2024 - Present

Worked in partnership with a software developer I trained with at Northcoders to build a google chrome extension that visualises audio from a tab. My role was UI/UX Design, Front-end Development, developing custom shaders using GLSL, 3D Graphics, Graphic Design and Identity Design. The project is currently in Open Beta and we are conducting User research which will inform the next round of development.

Freelance Web Developer | Reine Creative Mar 2024- Aug 2024

Designed and built a website for a freelance film-maker who trades under the name Reine Creative. In addition to Web Design & Development, I also worked on Service Design, Identity Design and Graphic Design.

Freelance Industrial Designer | Various Clients Dec 2016 - Present

Designed and developed new products to be integrated into existing ranges, created 3D CAD models, consulted on potential routes to market, manufacturing methods and creating a cohesive visual language for their product range. I worked on a variety of projects from jewelry to garden products. I still get approached by existing clients although I am now looking to work on the design and development of digital products and services.

Industrial Designer | Techstyle-Europe Dec 2013 - Oct 2016

Completed an apprenticeship in industrial design and continued to work there as a full time industrial designer for a further year. My role had a strong emphasis on design for manufacture which has led to a development centered approach to design and a skillset in 3D modelling, Rendering, Mechanical Design, UX Design, Graphic Design, Identity Design and Technical Communication.

Skills

Languages:

Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, C++, Python & GLSL

Testing:

Test Driven Development, Jest & Supertest

Back-end:

SQL, PSQL, Seeding & Migrations

Front-end:

React, React Native, Tailwind, Next.js, Three.js, React Fiber, Framer-Motion, p5.js, Plasmo

Technologies:

Node.js, Supabase, GitHub, Adobe Creative Suite, Figma, Blender

Product Design:

User journey mapping,
Persona's, Graphic Design,
Identity Design, UI/UX Design,
Intellectual property protection,
Technical communication, Rapid
Prototyping, Parametric 3D
Modelling, Programming &
Algorithm Aided 3D Modelling

Naveed Gujral Designer/Developer

Education

Northcoders | Software Development Course Oct 2023 - Jan 2024

BSc Product Design Technology (Hons) | 2:1 | UWE Sep 2018 - May 2021

Barnsley College | Product Design Apprenticeship Jan 2013 - Jan 2015

Level 3 NVQ:

Design

Level 3 BTEC Subsidiary Diploma:

• Art & Design | Distinction

Heckmondwike Grammar School 2007 to 2011

A Level

- Mathematics (A)
- Product Design (A*)
- Physics (A)

AS Level:

Further Mathematics (A)

GCSE:

- Design and Technology Resistant Materials (A)
- · Biology (A)
- Mathematics (A)
- Physics (A)
- English Language (B)
- Chemistry (B)
- Business Studies (B)
- Statistics (B)
- French (C)
- English Literature (C)
- Art & Design (C)

Level 2 BTEC:

Digital Applications | Merit

www.linkedin.com/in/naveed-gujral naveedgujral93@gmail.com

github.com/NaveedGujral naveedgujral.co.uk

Nottingham, UK

07954 048 430

Interests

3D Modelling, 3D Printing & Arduino

I enjoy experimenting and making things in my spare time using the skills I developed as a product designer. I enjoy learning new skills and technologies but I also find that the skills I develop can be transferable in unexpected ways.

Muay Thai

To keep fit I train in Muay Thai, which I have done since I was a teenager. The martial art has a vast amount of theory and techniques to learn and refine which is the reason it has kept my interest for such a long time. The discipline, respect and the desire to continuously develop has shaped my attitude as a professional.

Poetry, Music & Art

I often go to open-mic poetry nights and perform. I find pushing myself outside of my comfort zone can be a valuable experience and it has made me a more confident public speaker and writer. I also enjoy attending live electronic music nights and going to art exhibitions, which helps to inspire my own creative work and to meet like-minded people.